<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>yotzincortes.com</title>
    <description>Right here, right now.
</description>
    <link>http://yotzincortes.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yotzincortes.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 23:27:31 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 23:27:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Omnichannel experiences in eCommerce pt. 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;{This post was originally posted &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.crowdint.com/2014/03/11/omnichannel-experiences-in-ecommerce-pt-2.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing from the ideas on this older &lt;a href=&quot;http://yotzincortes.com/ecommerce/2015/07/28/Omnichannel-experiences-in-eCommerce-pt1.1.html&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; and a webinar on omnichannel from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.userzoom.com&quot;&gt;UserZoom&lt;/a&gt; I have recently attended, I’d like to share a bit more of information about omnichannel experiences. More specifically: how to create them and how crucial they are to increase and expand your customer base and sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;First things first: the difference between single, multi, cross and omnichannel experiences.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s begin by defining the predecessors of the omnichannel eCommerce:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Single channel&lt;/em&gt;: in this type of contact with the client, there’s only one way to offer your product or service to your customers, e.g: you have your store in a  website, but there’s no mobile version or native application for iOS or Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Multi channel&lt;/em&gt;: this type of contact considers more than one line of servicing the customer, but each channel has an independent user experience, e.g: an ecommerce that has a website and a tablet app, but without the possibility of combining the navigation data of each channel to offer a more personalized experience to the customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cross channel&lt;/em&gt;: this form of customer contact allows for several channels and the transfer of the customer data across them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Omnichannel&lt;/em&gt;: considers all touch points and channels as a single entity, constantly connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Omnichannel shoppers, who are they?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, research has been done about the identity of those shoppers who expect omnichannel experiences. Here are some typical characteristics, do they sound familiar to you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;They spend more than multichannel and single channel shoppers. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;They influence others. They become your brand ambassadors via their social network interactions and other types of online activity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;They exhibit strong loyalty to your brand, which leads to free word-of-mouth publicity for your business :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;They are very demanding and expect an immersive and intuitive experience on all channels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three subtypes of omnichannel shoppers, which are: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrated&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is economically stable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is 30 to 50 years old&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is well connected at home and at the office. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Young mobile&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is younger than 30&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is always on the move&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Texts a lot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Social Networker&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is usually young&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is driven by very specific interests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking into consideration those characteristics we will be able to tend to the needs of our omnichannel shoppers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;How to build omnichannel experiences:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the departments involved in the creation and maintenance of your store should work very closely. Marketing, IT and sales have to work in synchrony towards the same goal of offering a seamless experience for your customers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now, how do you actually achieve omnichannel? Here are some &lt;strong&gt;suggestions&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Model transitions and predict changes in the user experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foresee switching of channels and track them, what are they telling you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do it early: build maps of your store and the experience at every section. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do it often: revise and perfect your experience design. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider all touch points: physical, digital and human, they have to be in sync, offering the same experience. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow and observe your customer behaviour. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know your customer, look for workarounds, what do they need to adjust to? identify it and make an improvement to their experience, innovate!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrate: Service Design  + UX + CX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What’s in it for you business?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have a lot to gain if you offer omnichannel experiences for your customers in your store. Consider this single fact: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.retailtouchpoints.com/in-store-insights/2087-omnichannel-shoppers-to-spend-71-more-than-single-channel-consumers-this-holiday-season&quot;&gt;omnichannel shoppers spend 71% more than single channel shoppers.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! Don’t forget to follow &lt;a href=&quot;twitter.com/yotzin&quot;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;twitter.com/crowdint&quot;&gt;Crowd Interactive&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;References:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the information put forward here was acquired via a webinar from &lt;a href=&quot;twitter.com/userzoom&quot;&gt;User Zooom&lt;/a&gt;, which draws from the white paper titled &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marketresearch.com/IDC-v2477/Satisfying-Omnichannel-Consumers-Whenever-Wherever-2463981/view-related/&quot;&gt;Satisfying the Omnichannel Consumers Whenever and Wherever They Shop by IDC&lt;/a&gt;.
I also used the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com.mx/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=2&amp;amp;ved=0CC8QFjAB&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.webcredible.co.uk%2Fuser-friendly-resources%2Fwhite-papers%2Fomni-channel-report-2012.pdf&amp;amp;ei=HmQOU87lDOOYyAHxrIDQBg&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNG4SF9_PA6auFKW2c61Ev9LRrC1Hw&amp;amp;sig2=u2FKqFM_rwE5WXsAu5ik8Q&amp;amp;bvm=bv.61965928,d.aWc&amp;amp;cad=rja&quot;&gt;omnichannel user experience report by Webcredible &lt;/a&gt; as a reference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 15:20:31 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yotzincortes.github.io/ecommerce/2014/03/26/Omnichannel-experiences-in-eCommerce-pt2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yotzincortes.github.io/ecommerce/2014/03/26/Omnichannel-experiences-in-eCommerce-pt2.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>ecommerce</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Omnichannel experiences in eCommerce pt.1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;{This post was originally posted &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.crowdint.com/2014/03/11/omnichannel-experiences-in-ecommerce-pt-1.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine that you want to buy a video streaming player. It’s early in the day, before going out for work, and you use your laptop to do a bit of research online. You find that the most popular options today are the Apple TV, Roku and Chromecast players. You go through the technical specs for each device and then close down your laptop to have breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During lunchtime, you use the desktop computer at work to browse over reviews for the different players, and even save a couple of links. Later in the day, you use your iPad to compare prices at Pricegrabber and find the best offer at Amazon. You decide to consider all of the information you have acquired so far and ponder it before making the final decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After work, you use your Android-powered smartphone to ask around your friends and connections on Facebook and Twitter about their experiences and opinions about the devices in question. Very quickly, you get plenty of responses. You focus on the most useful ones and move on with your purchase. A minute later, you head straight to Amazon and buy the Chromecast, because it matches your needs and budget, and also because of the positive comments expressed by your friends on the social networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that buying experience rang any bells for you, then you are, like me, what digital commerce experts are now calling a Connected Consumer. This type of consumer is typically well informed about the item or service he is looking for, and expects the retailer to know more and offer support to complete the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in a nutshell, and looking back at the story we described above, Omnichannel eCommerce refers to the purchase experience integration offered by vendors and stores across OS platforms like Android and iOS, and devices such as laptops, smartphones and tablets. Imagine that your eCommerce business could offer a unified experience to your customers all the way from the moment they started thinking about buying until checking out your product or service, using the trail of information left behind by their browsing course. That’s omnichannel, and why do you need it? Well, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/media-network-partner-zone-ebay/omni-channel-retailers-connected-consumers&quot;&gt;the future of eCommerce is going that way&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To describe this in a more graphical way, here’s an infographic from David Sealey of Smart Insights:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ciblogassets.s3.amazonaws.com/crowdblog/asset/239/What-is-Omnichannel.png&quot; alt=&quot;image alt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, omnichannel experiences are all about the improvement of the customer experience with the intention of making a brand advocate who will bring more customers to your store. Let’s not forget &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paypromedia.com/2013/07/19/there-is-no-i-in-customer-the-importance-of-word-of-mouth-marketing/&quot;&gt;the power of word of mouth advertising&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some ways to integrate omnichannel experiences in your store:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrating customer reviews&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adding social media capabilities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remembering the buying preferences of your customers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll discuss more about this topic in this other post.
  Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 15:20:31 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yotzincortes.github.io/ecommerce/2014/03/11/Omnichannel-experiences-in-eCommerce-pt1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yotzincortes.github.io/ecommerce/2014/03/11/Omnichannel-experiences-in-eCommerce-pt1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>ecommerce</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to improve your English skills as a web dev (or as a normal person!)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;{This post was originally posted &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.crowdint.com/2014/01/28/how-to-improve-your-english-skills.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not a native speaker of English and are looking for ways to improve your language skills, I’d like to share some ideas with you. This post was written from my experience as an English learner and teacher. During the time I have been fulfilling the position of English advisor at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crowdint.com/&quot;&gt;Crowd Interactive&lt;/a&gt;, I have learned to identify some of the most useful ways to improve the language skills of someone who works in software development. But this post was also influenced by the feedback I received from many of my coworkers when I asked the question: “what are some strategies that have helped you improve your English?” (and I thank them for their input).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You surely know by now the reasons why you should take your English skills to the highest possible level; your command of the language will have a direct impact in your success in the web-development world. It doesn’t matter what role you would like to have now or in the future, developer, project manager or CTO, the importance of your English level will just continue getting more and more relevant as you climb up the ladder of the company ranks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some companies have hired English experts to help them create and run English programs. If you work for one of those companies, take advantage of the help of that person as much as you can, but never forget that the one who is ultimately responsible for your own learning is no one but yourself. So, roll up your sleeves and get down to work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Look for materials from reputable sources.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are literally millions of resources to learn languages, and English in particular, in the web. That’s why it may be a bit tricky to choose the ones you can really trust. Cambridge and Oxford have been in the business of teaching English as a foreign language for a very long time, and they have the reputation of being two of the best universities in the world for a reason. Both Cambridge University Press and Oxford University Press have dedicated websites to showcase their digital materials, check them out here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cambridgeenglish.org/&quot;&gt;CUP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://elt.oup.com/?cc=mx&amp;amp;selLanguage=enuniversities&quot;&gt;OUP&lt;/a&gt;. A notable example of an app from Cambridge is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.englishmonstruo.org/&quot;&gt;English Monstruo&lt;/a&gt;. If your first language is Spanish this is a great tool to polish your English. The app is made up of a series of highly addictive mini-games that make use of the most common mistakes made by Spanish speakers in the EFL examinations conducted by Cambridge every year. There’s a version for both Android and iOS, so check it out in each corresponding software store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Use Duolingo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of apps to learn English out there, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.duolingo.com/&quot;&gt;Duolingo&lt;/a&gt; is by far the best. The key to its success is gamification. Duolingo looks like a videogame, and hooks you like a videogame. It’s completely free, and there are lessons for every level of proficiency in several languages (English included). After you are done with the lessons (or earlier, if you ever feel like skipping them) you move on to the translation exercises. There you translate real websites, and can see discussions about the meaning of phrases or expressions initiated by other Duolingo users. It even has a function to improve your pronunciation by talking to the app, which isn’t perfect (I’ve noticed that sometimes it doesn’t recognize a well-pronounced phrase) but it can still be useful. The only thing that Duolingo can’t really do for you is develop your speaking skills, but other than that, it’s a great tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Read as if your life depended on it.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading helps you become aware of the conventions of the English language. Read as much as you can, technical and non-technical stuff, and make a habit of sharing what you read with others, as that will help to increase your retention rate. Make sure that the resources you use to find answers when you get stuck trying to fix a bug or writing a feature are in English. Sometimes we tend to find answers in our native language, but that won’t help you at all. Use every piece of vocabulary you just learned in an appropriate context of your life to imprint it on your brain, and discuss it with other people to confirm its meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Music is your best friend.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the lyrics of the artists you like and translate them into your native language. Don’t stop at the literal meaning and try and get the metaphorical meaning. Watch TV shows with English subtitles on and then without subtitles. Listen to audiobooks too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Develop the craft of writing.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great way of sharing what you read is by writing about it. Start a personal blog where you share your views about any topic that interests you. Don’t worry about having a big audience at first, the point is to process the ideas in your mind for your own benefit. Share your thoughts in writing and share your entries with friends and colleagues and start discussions. Alternatively, you can make the commitment of contributing with a collective blog, that can help with the discipline of writing regularly. Don’t fall into the habit of overgeneralizing about everything, make the effort of finding the right word for the idea you want to express as it will increase your vocabulary substantially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Oral expression is king.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, your ultimate goal is to SPEAK in English with your clients and colleagues, right? So, talk, talk, and then talk some more. Your speaking skills, like any other skills, can only be developed if they are put into practice. Talk as much as possible with as many people as possible, native or non-native speakers of English. Do in English the things you would normally do in Spanish. Speaking is a complex ability that gets better over time, and requires as much exposure to the language as you can get. Don’t worry about being corrected. Embrace any corrections coming your way, and be thankful for people’s feedback about your language skills. Remember that even native speakers make pronunciation mistakes from time to time. Set off to improve your skills following these guidelines and I assure you will notice results quicker than you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this is useful. Please let me know of any other strategies you put into practice to improve your English in the comments section, or hit me up on Twitter. Peace out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 15:20:31 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yotzincortes.github.io/english/dev/2014/01/28/How-to-improve-your-English-skills-(as-a-dev).html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yotzincortes.github.io/english/dev/2014/01/28/How-to-improve-your-English-skills-(as-a-dev).html</guid>
        
        
        <category>english</category>
        
        <category>dev</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
