<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>yotzincortes.com</title>
    <description>Right here, right now. &lt;/br&gt; Corvus oculum corvi non eruit.
</description>
    <link>http://yotzincortes.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yotzincortes.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 11:49:27 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 11:49:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quisqueyá</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;“A veces abajo de la superficie, a veces arriba…”&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Hombre al agua – Soda Estereo&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hace poco tuve la oportunidad de estar en República Dominicana, aquí comparto algunas de mis impresiones. Lo que vi:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;4&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/p/7DTHFYCWl_/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Yotzín Cortés-Medina (@yotzin1)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2015-08-31T14:43:59+00:00&quot;&gt;Aug 31, 2015 at 7:43am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Santo Domingo:&lt;/b&gt; donde pasé la mayor parte del tiempo, alojado en casa de Karen y sus amable amigos, anfitriones extraordinarios. En la ciudad está la primera calle empedrada de América (you heard that right). La primera Universidad del nuevo mundo. Los ruinas de los edificios levantados por los conquistadores. La casa donde se dice se planeó el viaje de Cortés a México (!!!!). Todo un viaje el darse cuenta en dónde está parado uno.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Samaná:&lt;/b&gt; la isla enfrente de la isla. En. El. Caribe. ¿Necesito decir más? Arenas blancas, Aguas turquesa cristalinas. Estaba prácticamente sola porque fuimos entre semana, un deleite. Llegamos en lancha motorizada, pasamos unas horas haciendo yoga en la playa y nadando. Al regreso comimos pescado en una chozita con los locales. De ensueño.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Laguna Azul de Dudú:&lt;/b&gt; un par de cenotes en medio de la selva. Aguas tan claras que parecían espejos. Me tiré desde la cuerda que pendía por sobre el agua y debo haber caído unos 20 metros. ¡Ola!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Neptuno’s:&lt;/b&gt; un restaurant espectacular en la playa de Boca Chica (la más popular y cercana a Santo Domingo). Es más bien como un puertecito desde el que uno se puede aventar directamente a las aguas del Caribe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Juan Dolio:&lt;/b&gt; playa adjacente a Boca Chica. Y Boca Chica tiene relevancia para mi  porque es parte de lo que visitó Anthony Bourdain en su episodio de No Reservations grabado acá. Véanlo, no tiene desperdicio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bonyé:&lt;/b&gt; grupo de ritmos tropicales que toca todos los domingos en las ruinas de la zona colonial en Santo Domingo. Bailamos (bailé) con reducidas inhibiciones estimulado por el ron Brugal sabor chinola en forma de hielo raspado. Fabuloso. Esta fue probablemente la major noche de todas. Bonyé tocó “El cuarto de Tula”, de mis favoritas de Buenavista Social Club. Satisfacción pura (hay foto, no miento).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Constanza:&lt;/b&gt; las montañas. Un pueblito enclavado en la cordillera principal de la isla. Aquí visitamos el salto Aguas Blancas, una cascada muy parecida a El Salto en Colima, pero alta y vistosa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bayahibe:&lt;/b&gt; desde aquí escribo hoy. A dos horas de Santo Domingo (en dirección a Punta Cana), esta playa es un paraíso natural no  demasidado aglomerado. Me quedé en un resort super cómodo, a decirle adios a la isla en formato uno a uno.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;4&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/p/7EsxuhiWq7/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Yotzín Cortés-Medina (@yotzin1)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2015-09-01T03:47:30+00:00&quot;&gt;Aug 31, 2015 at 8:47pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y aprendí:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Que los dominicanos manejan como si no existiera reglamento de tránsito, lo cual convierte la experiencia de ir tras del volante en una frenética carrera de obstáculos . Parece broma, pero es en serio. Por un par de días manejé y estuve a punto de ser chocado por vehículos que salían out of nowhere, y no tenían razón par estar tan cerca. Tiende a ser frustrante. Los carros se detienen en cualquier lugar por cualquier razón (a veces solo para saludar a sus amigos). Se detienen en medio de la carretera. Se van en reversa de la nada, ¡EN LA CARRETERA! Hay motociclistas por todos lados, yendo en todas direcciones, siguiendo ninguna regla de tránsito. Todo se vale, todo se puede, y todos se quejan pero todos manejan igual de mal. Y te ven como si no entendieran qué te hicieron cuando les reclamas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Que en la República Dominicana se consume muchísima multimedia Mexicana. Especialmente música y telenovelas. Ejemplos: caminando en las calles noté familias mirando los últimos tele-dramas de Televisa. Y en la carretera rumbo a Bayahibe, el taxista me dijo que si podia poner una musiquita tranquilita; eran los éxitos de José José.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Que se puede disfrutar muchísimo viniendo incluso solo a una playa del Caribe. Estoy descansando, viviendo, experimentando. Disfruto las comidas. Tomo el café despacio. Me río de la nada solo por sentirme libre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hoy mientras nadaba solo en el mar me di cuenta de que haber venido acá no fue casualidad. Algo dentro de mi sabía lo bueno que podía ser. Las claras y salinas aguas del mar limpian el cuerpo. Y el alma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;EXTRA:&lt;/b&gt; en realidad tengo tres historias más que no pondré aquí de momento. A la primera la llamo el episodio cinematográfico e involucra un accidente automotriz  (!!!). A la segunda la llamo “a que no sabes qué es un volcán”. Y la tercera: “de cómo me encontré al presidente de la RD en un pueblito en la montaña”. Esas las dejaré para que me las preguntes en persona la siguiente veas que te vea (sí, tú, amigx lector). Son interesantes, lo garantizo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y ahora, vocabulario nuevo. Practice with a classmate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chinola = maracuyá.&lt;br /&gt;
Dembow = no es reggaetón, pero se parece.&lt;br /&gt;
Chapi = mujer de la vida fácil.&lt;br /&gt;
“Tigere” (tigre) = hombre conquistador.&lt;br /&gt;
¡Ya tu sabeh! = “Tú sabes cómo es esa cosa”.&lt;br /&gt;
Mofongo = orgullo nacional, puré de plátano con queso y especias.&lt;br /&gt;
Menudo = dinero suelto.&lt;br /&gt;
Plaza bolera = el boliche.&lt;br /&gt;
“Tohtone” (tostones) = rebanadas de plátano frito.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/b&gt; agrego esto el vuelo de regreso a México pasando por Panamá. Voy en camiseta, shorts y chancletas. Traigo todavía el aroma del aceite del masaje que tomé esta mañana. Tomo cerveza Panamá Lager. En la ventana se ve el caribe tapizado de nubecillas blancas. Regularmente los regresos de viaje me hacen perder la relajación que había conseguido en la playa, pero esta vez no ha sido así. Sigo con la relajación bien instalada en el cuerpo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;4&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/p/7EA64PiWjn/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Yotzín Cortés-Medina (@yotzin1)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2015-08-31T21:24:17+00:00&quot;&gt;Aug 31, 2015 at 2:24pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Si quieres ver más fotos, míralas en &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/yotzin1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mi cuenta de Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 16:20:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yotzincortes.github.io/travel,/life/2015/09/20/Quisqueya.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yotzincortes.github.io/travel,/life/2015/09/20/Quisqueya.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>travel,</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mi proyecto para Dev.f</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hola:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El día de hoy me gradué del programa Dev.f, y aquí les dejo el video donde presento mi proyecto final, que es este mismo blog (so meta!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NFB0PxV0Fws&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;¡Saludos!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 16:20:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yotzincortes.github.io/english-dev/2015/08/21/Mi-proyecto-para-Dev.f.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yotzincortes.github.io/english-dev/2015/08/21/Mi-proyecto-para-Dev.f.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>english-dev</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Podcast en ClicFM Radio</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hola:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hemos grabado un podcast con los amigos de &lt;a href=&quot;http://clicfm.org&quot;&gt;ClicFM Radio&lt;/a&gt; sobre cómo mejorar tu inglés como developer, chéquenlo y dejen sus comentarios o preguntas &lt;a href=&quot;http://clicfm.org/category/eby/&quot;&gt;acá&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 16:20:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yotzincortes.github.io/english-dev/2015/08/20/Podcast-en-ClicFM-Radio.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yotzincortes.github.io/english-dev/2015/08/20/Podcast-en-ClicFM-Radio.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>english-dev</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>La experiencia Dev.f</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Esperé por AÑOS para tener una experiencia como la del &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.devf.mx/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dev.f&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En los últimos tres años de mi vida he estado trabajando directa o indirectamente con equipos de desarrollo y me he sentido inspirado a aprender más del oficio. Pero como es fácil de imaginarse, con un trabajo de tiempo completo, dos hijos y una madre enferma es dificil encontrar el tiempo. #Noscierto. No tengo dos hijos. Y mi madre goza de buena salud. Pero sí he estado trabajando de tiempo completo sin parar desde que terminé la universidad y recientemente terminé una maestría al mismo tiempo que trabajaba. The dictionary definition of a tight schedule, maybe?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La verdad es que en la prepa hice una carrera técnica, y llegué a programar en Pascal y C++. Mas decidí brincar a las humanidades y me matriculé a la facultad de lenguas extranjeras de la &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ucol.mx/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Universidad de Colima&lt;/a&gt;. Fui profesor de español e inglés como lenguas extranjeras por unos años luego de egresar, luego hice una maestría en lingüística aplicada. Y fue justamente a media maestría que la oportunidad de unirme a Crowd Interactive hizo que regresara a la industría de la tecnología. A vuelta de dos años, I landed a job as a product owner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://tangosource.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TangoSource&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My way towards Dev.f started a couple years ago actually. I met Manuel Morato at &lt;a href=&quot;http://magmaconf.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MagmaConf 2014&lt;/a&gt;. You can read about his experience &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ememorato/a-summary-of-magmaconf2014-f95d2bb83736&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; Then, about a year later, I read that he was starting a dev school. The thought had been on my mind since the boom of the dev bootcamps in San Francisco a few months earlier. So, I found the time (and the money) to do it and went for it. When the folks at work agreed that I worked remotely for eight weeks, I hesitated no more and sent my application immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During these eight weeks, in cinta blanca, we have covered the basics of HTML5 and CSS3, as well as some Javascript. This is a good starting point for anyone who wants to delve deeper into web dev. In my personal case, it will help me communicate better with the group of devs with which I interact every day. And enables me the tools to build simple web things myself, or adapt them to my needs.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product of my time here is this blog, which serves as my personal website. Earlier, I had it hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.squarespace.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; and used their CMS to build it. Now, I used &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, a pretty cool blog-building framework. In combination with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/hosting&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; service, there’s nothing else you would need to create an awesome blog. I configured the DNS so that it will work with the domain I had already bought, implemented a &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; comments system and enabled Github emoji. And here you have it. It isn’t complex stuff (in hacker terms), but it’s quite an achievement for a former language teacher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great feature of Dev.f is that it promotes not just coding skills, but also entrepreneurship, biz dev and the sense of community. During our time here, we had the chance to meet and listen to relevant figures of the tech industry such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/solsona&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Francisco Solsona&lt;/a&gt; (Developer relations manager at Google México)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/clrandall&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donna Randall&lt;/a&gt; (Co-founder of Conekta)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lulomx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Luis López Méndez&lt;/a&gt;, AKA “Lulo” (Product Designer at 23design)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jfmolina&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jorge Molina&lt;/a&gt; (Director of Google for Work México)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/andresbarreto&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Andrés Barreto&lt;/a&gt; (Co-founder of Grooveshark)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also had smaller side events, like the a night when we attended a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.campus-night.com.mx/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Campus Night&lt;/a&gt; at DF. And there was also the LOLathón, which (contrary to any logical conclusion), is not a League of Legends marathon, but a challenge to build apps “for the lolz”, just for the fun of it. I collaborated with a team who build “Get the f&lt;em&gt;ck App”, which helps those of us who have a REALLY hard time getting up early in the morning, by publishing shameful tweets and Facebook posts until we get the f&lt;/em&gt;ck up! :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that anyone who is interested in developing their hacking skills thinks no more and acts upon this opportunity. I can assure that you will not regret it. Ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter how old you are, or what your career path is. If you you happen to be very young and studied software engineering, then even better. At Dev.f you will polish your skills and connect with the startup scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/devfphoto.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dev.f&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about my experience at the Dev.f program, don’t hesitate to contact me via email, or posting your thoughts on the comments section below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 16:20:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yotzincortes.github.io/dev.f,/web-development/2015/08/15/La-experiencia-Dev.f.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yotzincortes.github.io/dev.f,/web-development/2015/08/15/La-experiencia-Dev.f.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>dev.f,</category>
        
        <category>web-development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Another culture post from TangoSource&#39;s blog!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello all,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another team member interview has just been published at TangoSource’s blog. You can check it out &lt;a href=&quot;http://tangosource.com/blog/get-to-know-our-team-cesar-gomez-web-developer/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 16:20:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yotzincortes.github.io/culture/2015/04/24/Another-culture-post-from-TangoSource's-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yotzincortes.github.io/culture/2015/04/24/Another-culture-post-from-TangoSource's-blog.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New culture post from TangoSource&#39;s blog!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello all,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A short team member interview that I performed has just been published at TangoSource’s blog. You can check it out &lt;a href=&quot;http://tangosource.com/blog/get-to-know-our-developers-ivan-velazquez-web-developer/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 15:20:31 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yotzincortes.github.io/culture/2015/01/28/New-culture-post-from-TangoSource's-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yotzincortes.github.io/culture/2015/01/28/New-culture-post-from-TangoSource's-blog.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Entrevista en EmpleosTI.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hola todos,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El día de hoy se ha publicado en &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.empleosti.com.mx&quot;&gt;EmpleosTI&lt;/a&gt; una entrevista con su servidor. La pregunta era qué recomendaciones generales se le pueden dar a los devs hablantes no-nativos de inglés para mejorar sus habilidades comunicativas. &lt;a href=&quot;http://empleosti.la/blog/6-tips-para-elevar-tu-nivel-de-ingles/&quot;&gt;Aquí se los dejo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 16:20:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yotzincortes.github.io/english-dev/2014/10/16/Entrevista-en-EmpleosTI.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yotzincortes.github.io/english-dev/2014/10/16/Entrevista-en-EmpleosTI.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>english-dev</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reseña de nuestra comunidad EnglishBecauseYOLO en EmpleosTI.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hola todos,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El día de hoy se ha publicado en &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.empleosti.com.mx&quot;&gt;EmpleosTI&lt;/a&gt; una reseña de nuestra comunidad para desarrollar tu inglés hablado como dev. Si te quieres enterar de más, &lt;a href=&quot;http://empleosti.la/blog/englishbecauseyolo-practica-tu-ingles-por-hangout/&quot;&gt;mira el video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 16:20:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yotzincortes.github.io/english-dev/2014/09/29/Resen%CC%83a-de-nuestra-comunidad-%23EnglishBecauseYOLO-publicada-en-empleosTI.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yotzincortes.github.io/english-dev/2014/09/29/Resen%CC%83a-de-nuestra-comunidad-%23EnglishBecauseYOLO-publicada-en-empleosTI.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>english-dev</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Recomendación de aplicación móvil para mejorar tu inglés, English Monstruo</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hola todos,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El día de hoy se ha publicado en &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.empleosti.com.mx&quot;&gt;EmpleosTI&lt;/a&gt; la recomendación de aplicación móvil para mejorar tu inglés que hice en una entrevista que tuve con ellos. &lt;a href=&quot;http://empleosti.la/blog/aprende-ingles-con-english-monstruo-app/&quot;&gt;Échenle un ojo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 16:20:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yotzincortes.github.io/english-dev/2014/09/29/Recomendacio%CC%81n-de-aplicacio%CC%81n-mo%CC%81vil-para-mejorar-tu-ingle%CC%81s-publicada-en-EmpleosTI.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yotzincortes.github.io/english-dev/2014/09/29/Recomendacio%CC%81n-de-aplicacio%CC%81n-mo%CC%81vil-para-mejorar-tu-ingle%CC%81s-publicada-en-EmpleosTI.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>english-dev</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Omnichannel experiences in eCommerce pt. 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;{This post was originally posted &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.crowdint.com/2014/03/11/omnichannel-experiences-in-ecommerce-pt-2.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing from the ideas on this older &lt;a href=&quot;http://yotzincortes.com/ecommerce/2015/07/28/Omnichannel-experiences-in-eCommerce-pt1.1.html&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; and a webinar on omnichannel from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.userzoom.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UserZoom&lt;/a&gt; I have recently attended, I’d like to share a bit more of information about omnichannel experiences. More specifically: how to create them and how crucial they are to increase and expand your customer base and sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;First things first: the difference between single, multi, cross and omnichannel experiences.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s begin by defining the predecessors of the omnichannel eCommerce:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Single channel&lt;/em&gt;: in this type of contact with the client, there’s only one way to offer your product or service to your customers, e.g: you have your store in a  website, but there’s no mobile version or native application for iOS or Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Multi channel&lt;/em&gt;: this type of contact considers more than one line of servicing the customer, but each channel has an independent user experience, e.g: an ecommerce that has a website and a tablet app, but without the possibility of combining the navigation data of each channel to offer a more personalized experience to the customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cross channel&lt;/em&gt;: this form of customer contact allows for several channels and the transfer of the customer data across them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Omnichannel&lt;/em&gt;: considers all touch points and channels as a single entity, constantly connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Omnichannel shoppers, who are they?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, research has been done about the identity of those shoppers who expect omnichannel experiences. Here are some typical characteristics, do they sound familiar to you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;They spend more than multichannel and single channel shoppers. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;They influence others. They become your brand ambassadors via their social network interactions and other types of online activity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;They exhibit strong loyalty to your brand, which leads to free word-of-mouth publicity for your business :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;They are very demanding and expect an immersive and intuitive experience on all channels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three subtypes of omnichannel shoppers, which are: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrated&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is economically stable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is 30 to 50 years old&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is well connected at home and at the office. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Young mobile&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is younger than 30&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is always on the move&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Texts a lot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Social Networker&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is usually young&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is driven by very specific interests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking into consideration those characteristics we will be able to tend to the needs of our omnichannel shoppers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to build omnichannel experiences:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the departments involved in the creation and maintenance of your store should work very closely. Marketing, IT and sales have to work in synchrony towards the same goal of offering a seamless experience for your customers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now, how do you actually achieve omnichannel? Here are some &lt;strong&gt;suggestions&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Model transitions and predict changes in the user experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foresee switching of channels and track them, what are they telling you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do it early: build maps of your store and the experience at every section. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do it often: revise and perfect your experience design. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider all touch points: physical, digital and human, they have to be in sync, offering the same experience. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow and observe your customer behaviour. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know your customer, look for workarounds, what do they need to adjust to? identify it and make an improvement to their experience, innovate!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrate: Service Design  + UX + CX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What’s in it for you business?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have a lot to gain if you offer omnichannel experiences for your customers in your store. Consider this single fact: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.retailtouchpoints.com/in-store-insights/2087-omnichannel-shoppers-to-spend-71-more-than-single-channel-consumers-this-holiday-season&quot;&gt;omnichannel shoppers spend 71% more than single channel shoppers.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! Don’t forget to follow &lt;a href=&quot;twitter.com/yotzin&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the information put forward here was acquired via a webinar from &lt;a href=&quot;twitter.com/userzoom&quot;&gt;User Zooom&lt;/a&gt;, which draws from the white paper titled &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marketresearch.com/IDC-v2477/Satisfying-Omnichannel-Consumers-Whenever-Wherever-2463981/view-related/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Satisfying the Omnichannel Consumers Whenever and Wherever They Shop by IDC&lt;/a&gt;.
I also used the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com.mx/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=2&amp;amp;ved=0CC8QFjAB&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.webcredible.co.uk%2Fuser-friendly-resources%2Fwhite-papers%2Fomni-channel-report-2012.pdf&amp;amp;ei=HmQOU87lDOOYyAHxrIDQBg&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNG4SF9_PA6auFKW2c61Ev9LRrC1Hw&amp;amp;sig2=u2FKqFM_rwE5WXsAu5ik8Q&amp;amp;bvm=bv.61965928,d.aWc&amp;amp;cad=rja&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;omnichannel user experience report by Webcredible&lt;/a&gt; as a reference.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 15:20:31 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yotzincortes.github.io/ecommerce/2014/03/26/Omnichannel-experiences-in-eCommerce-pt2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yotzincortes.github.io/ecommerce/2014/03/26/Omnichannel-experiences-in-eCommerce-pt2.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>ecommerce</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
